Register of the Baronessa Marii͡a Dmitrievna Vrangel' collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Part I (Boxes 2-38)
  - File 18, 1920-1935 (Boxes 23-24)
    - Russian educational institutions
      - Military Academies (Kadetskie Korpusa)
        - Korpus-Litsei imeni Naslednika TSesarevicha Alekseia Nikolaevicha (funded by A. Vonsiatskii), clipping, TSarskii Vestnik, April 1931 (Box 23, Folder 16)
        - Ob"edinenie Russkikh Kadet na CHuzhbine, bulletin and clipping, 1930 (Box 23, Folder 17)
        - Pervyi Russkii Velikago Kniazia Konstantina Konstantinovicha Kadetskii Korpus, Belaia TSerkov', miscellaneous material including correspondence with Gen. B. Adamovich and printed matter, 1924-1931 (Box 24, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 25
        - Clippings, 1934-1935 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Female Academies
        - KHar'kovskii Institut Imperatritsy Marii Feodorovny, miscellaneous material including correspondence with M. Nekliudova and typescript reports, 1929 (Box 24, Folder 3)
        - Mariinskii Donskoi Institut, typescript report, 1929 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Educational organizations
      - "Kruzhok 'K Poznaniiu o Rossii'", miscellaneous material, 1930-1931 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - "Lektsii o Rossii", miscellaneous material, including correspondence of Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller, programs of lectures and clippings, 1927-1930 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - "Russkai Matitsa", (Prof. A. Bilimovich), miscellaneous material including correspondence and printed matter, 1928-1930 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - File 19, 1924-1934 (Boxes 24-25)
    Institutions of higher learning. Miscellaneous material.
    - Institutions of higher learning, miscellaneous typescript and handwritten material
      - Bulgaria. Russkii Narodnyi Universitet v Sofii, undated (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Czechoslovakia (Box 24, Folder 9)
        - Russkii IUridicheskii Fakul'tet v Prage, (File 12) printed reports, 1925-1928
        - Russkii Narodnyi Universitet v Prage, 1924-1930 (Box 24, Folder 10)
        - Russkii Zagranichnyi Istoricheskii Arkhiv v Prage, includes correspondence with V. CHernavin, 1928-1933 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - France
        - Franco-Russkii Institut, miscellaneous material, 1930 (Box 25, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 26
        - Kommercheskii Institut v Parizhe, 1931 (Box 25, Folder 2)
        - Russkaia Politekhnicheskaia SHkola, 1921-1931 (Box 25, Folder 3)
        - Russkii Narodnyi Universitet v Parizhe, 1922-1931 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Latvia. List of professors, 1933 and Russkie Universitetskie Kursy v Rige, 1922 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Yugoslavia. Russkii Narodnyi Universitet v Belgrade, 1926-1929 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Clippings, 1931-1934
  - File 20, 1920-1932 (Boxes 25-26)
    Ob"edinenie Rossiiskikh Zemskikh i Gorodskikh Deiatelei (Zemgor) and Vserossiiskii Zemskii Soiuz. Miscellaneous material.
    - Ob"edinenie Rossiiskikh Zemskikh i Gorodskikh Deiatelei (Zemgor)
      - Reports, printed copies
        - Biulleten', January-July 1930 (Box 25, Folder 7)
        - Obzor Deiatel'nosti Vremennogo Glavnogo Komiteta Vserossiiskogo Soiuza Gorodov Zagranitsei za g.g., 1920-1926 (Box 25, Folder 8)
        - Otchet o Deiatel'nosti Predstavitel'stva Vserossiiskago Soiuza Gorodov v Korolevstve S.KH.S. za 1924 god, 1925 (Box 25, Folder 9)
        - Otchet o Deiatel'nosti Rossiiskago Zemsko-Gorodskogo Komiteta pomoshchi rossiiskim grazhdanam za-granitsei, Paris, 1922 (Box 25, Folder 10)
        - Ocherk Deiatel'nosti Ob"edineniia Rossiiskikh Zemskikh i Gorodskikh Deiateleiv CHechoslovatskoi Respubliki "Zemgor", 1925 (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Oeuvre de secours de l'Union des Villes de la Russie aux enfants russes émigrés, 1922 (Box 25, Folder 12)
        - Pomoshch' Detiam, 1930 (Box 25, Folder 13)
        - "Pravila o ssudo-sberegatel'noi kasse sluzhashchikh Zemgora", 1925 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence, 1928-1929 (Box 25, Folder 15)
      - Clippings and photographs, 1930-1932 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Vserossiiskii Zemskii Soiuz
      - Reports, printed copies
        - Crédit Mutuel Union, 1931 (Box 26, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 27
        - "Deiatel'nost' V.Z.S. v Bolgarii", tearsheets, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
        - Review of the Activity of the All Russian Zemstvo Union, 1921 (Box 26, Folder 3)
        - Vserossiiskii Zemskii Soiuz, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, A. KHripu, nov, 1927 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - File 21, 1919-1932 (Boxes 26-27)
    Russian literature in exile. Includes correspondence, biographies, autobiographies and printed matter.
    - Russian literature in exile
      - Correspondence, clippings and printed matter, mostly biographical material
        - Aldanov, M., March 1930 (Box 26, Folder 6)
        - Amfiteatrov, A., 1929-1930 (Box 26, Folder 7)
        - Andreev, L., "S.O.S.", printed brochure, 1919 (Box 26, Folder 8)
        - Bal'mont, K., clipping, 1930 (Box 26, Folder 9)
        - Bariatinskii, Prince V., January 1932 (Box 26, Folder 10)
        - Berberova, N., April 1931 (Box 26, Folder 11)
        - Boldyreva, T., December 1929-October 1932 (Box 26, Folder 12)
        - Bunin, I., includes clippings re Nobel Prize, March-May 1931-1933 (Box 26, Folder 13)
        - CHirikov, E., 1931 (Box 26, Folder 14)
        - Elachich, E., September 1930 (Box 26, Folder 15)
        - Elenev, N., December 1932 (Box 26, Folder 16)
        - Evgrafov, P., 1930 (Box 26, Folder 17)
        - Galich-Goncharenko, Maj.-Gen. IU., October 1931 (Box 26, Folder 18)
        - Gippius, Z., July 1931 (Box 26, Folder 19)
        - Grebenshchikov, G., 1930-1931 (Box 26, Folder 20)
        - Kasatkin-Rostovskii, Prince F., June 1933 (Box 26, Folder 21)
        - KHodasevich, V., March 1931 (Box 26, Folder 22)
        - Krasnov, P., May 1931 (Box 26, Folder 23)
        - Krechetov, S. (Sokolov), July 1932 (Box 26, Folder 24)
        - Kul'man, N., December 1928-February 1930 (Box 26, Folder 25)
        - Kuprin, A., 1931 (Box 26, Folder 26)
        - Kuznetsova, G., April 1931 (Box 26, Folder 27)
        - Landau, G., July 1933 (Box 26, Folder 28)
        - Lukash, I., April 1930-March 1931 (Box 26, Folder 29)
        - Mintslov, S., March 1931 (Box 26, Folder 30)
        - Nabokov, V., July 1931 (Box 26, Folder 31)
        - Nazhivin, I., April 1930 (Box 26, Folder 32)
        - Nemirovich-Danchenko, V., February 1932 (Box 26, Folder 33)
        - Nol'ken, Baron I., March 1932 (Box 26, Folder 34)
        - Novakovskaia, N., November 1931 (Box 26, Folder 35)
        - Osorgin, M., March 1931 (Box 26, Folder 36)
        - Otsup, A. (Gornyi, S.), April 1932 (Box 26, Folder 37)
        - Peskov, G. (Deisha E.), July 1931 (Box 26, Folder 38)
        - Pushkin, N.A., centennial of Pushkin's death, February-March 1937 (Box 26, Folder 39)
        - Remizov, A., May 1931 (Box 26, Folder 40)
        - Rennikov, A., 1932 (Box 26, Folder 41)
        - Roshchin, N., June-Aug, 1931 (Box 26, Folder 42)
        - Rybinskii, N., March 1930-1931 (Box 26, Folder 43)
        - Sazonova, IU., undated (Box 26, Folder 44)
        - SHmelev, I., 1931 (Box 26, Folder 45)
        - Teffi, N., 1931 (Box 26, Folder 46)
        - Tolstoy. I., May 1931 (Box 27, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 28
        - Vrangel', Baron N., clippings of reviews, Ot Krepostnogo Prava do Bol'shevizma, 1924 (Box 27, Folder 2)
        - Zaitsev, B., May 1931 (Box 27, Folder 3)
        - Zavadskii, V. (Korsak, V.), undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
        - Zurov, L., 1930-1931 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Clippings
        - General, includes bibliographical material, 1929-1934 (Box 27, Folder 6)
        - Poetry, 1922-1927 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - File 22, 1924-1932 (Boxes 27-28)
    Russian press. Miscellaneous material.
    - Russian press
      - Correspondence, Hessen, G. von, editor of Rul', April 1929-June 1931 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Russkaia Zarubezhnaia Kniga, printed copy, Prague, 1924 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - Soiuz Russkikh Pisatelei i Zhurnalistov, miscellaneous material, including correspondence of individuals involved in journalism
        - Czechoslovakia, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 10)
        - France, 1931 (Box 27, Folder 11)
        - Germany, 1924-1927 (Box 27, Folder 12)
        - Yugoslavia, September 1928 (Box 27, Folder 13)
      - Newspaper clippings, catalogs, lists of book and periodical publications, 1929-1933 (Box 28, Folder 1-4)
        Available on microfilm reel 29
  - File 23-24, 1920-1936 (Boxes 28-30)
    Russian music. Includes correspondence, biographies, autobiographies and printed matter including programs.
    - Russian music
      - Correspondence, including biographical material and printed matter
        - Aleksandrovich, A., June 1929 (Box 28, Folder 5)
        - Amfiteatrov, D., undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
        - Amfiteatrov, M., undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
        - CHerepnin, N. and Russkaia Konservatoriia v Parizhe, January 1930-June 1931 (Box 28, Folder 8)
        - CHerkaskaia, M., March 1930 (Box 28, Folder 9)
        - Davydov, A., June 1930 (Box 28, Folder 10)
        - El-Tour, A., January-August 1930 (Box 28, Folder 11)
        - Flamburiari, D., February 1936 (Box 28, Folder 12)
        - Grechaninov, A., correspondence, and printed program, December 1931, June 1929-April 1930 (Box 28, Folder 13)
        - IAkovleva, A., 1931 (Box 28, Folder 14)
        - Il'iashchenko, A., November 1932 (Box 28, Folder 15)
        - Kedrov, N. and Gladkaia-Kedrova, S., February 1930 (Box 28, Folder 16)
        - Kurenki, M, December 1931 (Box 28, Folder 17)
        - Kusevitskii, S. (letter of N. Bekhtereva), October 1929 (Box 28, Folder 18)
        - Labinskii, A., March 1930-April 1932 (Box 29, Folder 1)
        - Lipkovskaia, L., 1929 (Box 29, Folder 2)
        - Manteufel-Schwarz, T., June 1931 (Box 29, Folder 3)
        - Metner, N., March, 1932 (Box 29, Folder 4)
        - Pavlovskii, F., undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
        - Pomerantsev, IU., January-February 1932 (Box 29, Folder 6)
        - Rakhmaninov, S., March 1929-April 1931 (Box 29, Folder 7)
        - Riabushinskaia, V., 1936-1937 (Box 29, Folder 8)
        - Rombro-Braude, E., 1920 (Box 29, Folder 9)
        - Trebinskii, A., May 1932 (Box 29, Folder 10)
        - SHaliapin, F., clipping and program, 1928-1930 (Box 29, Folder 11)
        - Slatin, I., August 1930 (Box 29, Folder 12)
        - Val'ter, V., January 1930-April 1931 (Box 29, Folder 13)
        - Ziloti, A., July 1931-March 1932 (Box 29, Folder 14)
      - Choirs, miscellaneous material
        - General, 1929-1933 (Box 29, Folder 15)
        - "Obshchestudencheskii Russkii KHor Imeni A.A. Arkhangel'kago v Prage", includes Russkii KHorovoi Sbornik and Russkii KHorovoi Vestnik, 1923-1931 (Box 29, Folder 16)
          Available on microfilm reel 30
        - "Donskoi Kazachii KHor Sergeia A. ZHarova", 1930-1933 (Box 29, Folder 17)
        - "Russian Symphonic Choir", 1926-1929 (Box 29, Folder 18)
      - Printed matter
        - Le Théâtre et la vie, July 1930 (Box 29, Folder 19)
        - Clippings, including announcements and reviews of concerts, interviews with musicians and singers, 1929-1935 (Box 29, Folder 20-22)
      - Reports re Russian music, typescript
        - Barcelona, 1930 (Box 30, Folder 1)
        - Belgium, 1932 (Box 30, Folder 2)
        - Berlin, undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
        - Constantinople, undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - File 25-26-27, 1924-1934 (Boxes 30-32)
    Russian art and artists. Includes correspondence, biographies, autobiographies and printed matter including material re exhibits.
    - Russian art
      - Introduction, typescript, undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Correspodence, including biographical material and printed matter (Box 30)
        - Anisfeld, B., 1929 (Box 30, Folder 6)
        - Benoit, Aleksandr, January 1929-April 1930 (Box 30, Folder 7)
        - Benoit, Al'bert, January 1930 (Box 30, Folder 8)
        - Benoit, N., clipping, Oct 1931 (Box 30, Folder 9)
        - Beklemisheva, K., July 1932-February 1933 (Box 30, Folder 10)
        - Bilibin, I., October 1929 (Box 30, Folder 11)
        - Bogdanov-Bel'skii, N., May 1931 (Box 30, Folder 12)
        - Brailovskii, L. and Brailovskaia, R., February 1930-February 1932 (Box 30, Folder 13)
        - Deriuzhinskii, G., May 1929 (Box 30, Folder 14)
        - Dobuzhinskii, M., February 1929-March 1939 (Box 31, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 31
        - Dobuzhinskii, R., n.d (Box 31, Folder 2)
        - Globa, N., June 1931 (Box 31, Folder 3)
        - Grigor'ev, B., January 1930-February 1939. Includes printed copy of Raseia, brochures of exhibits and other printed matter. File 39 includes Boris Grigoriev Faces of Russia, limited edition printed copy, London, 1924. File 40 includes Boui Bouis, limited edition printed copy, Petropolis (Box 31, Folder 4-7)
        - IAkovlev, A., 1930 (Box 31, Folder 8)
        - IAshvil', Prince N., January 1930-September 1932 (Box 31, Folder 9)
        - Izmailovich, D., July, 1930 (Box 31, Folder 10)
        - Kolesnikov, S., October 1930 (Box 31, Folder 11)
        - Korovin, K., clippings, 1930 (Box 31, Folder 12)
        - Kosinskaia, T., August 1930-December 1934 (Box 31, Folder 13)
        - Lukomskii, G., includes printed matter re exhibitions, February 1930-July 1931 (Box 31, Folder 14-16)
        - Maliavin, F., clipping, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 1)
        - Milliotti, N., July 1929-September 1930 (Box 32, Folder 2)
        - "Obshchestvo Ikona", July 1931 (Box 32, Folder 3)
        - Oltarzhevskii, V., October 1929 (Box 32, Folder 4)
        - Perfil'ev, V., clipping, May 1929 (Box 32, Folder 5)
        - Repin, I., letter of V. Repina and IU. Repin and clippings, May-December 1930 (Box 32, Folder 6)
        - Roerich, N., includes printed matter re Master Institute, Roerich Museum and "Urusvati" Himalayan Research Institute, 1929-1932 (Box 32, Folder 7-8)
          Available on microfilm reels 31-32
        - Rundal'tsov, M., May 1930 (Box 32, Folder 9)
          Available on microfilm reel 32
        - SHervashidze, Prince A., July 1930 (Box 32, Folder 10)
        - SHchekotikhina, A., October 1939-October 1931 (Box 32, Folder 11)
        - SHiltian, G., 1930 (Box 32, Folder 12)
        - SHukhaev, V., April 1929-October 1931 (Box 32, Folder 13)
        - Serebriakova, Z., March 1929 (Box 32, Folder 14)
        - Somov, K., May 1930 (Box 32, Folder 15)
        - Sorin, S., August 1929 (Box 32, Folder 16)
        - Stashevskii, V., June 1930 (Box 32, Folder 17)
        - Stelletskii, D., January 1930-March 1932 (Box 32, Folder 18)
        - Sudeikin, S., 1930 (Box 32, Folder 19)
        - Telitsin, N., undated (Box 32, Folder 20)
        - Tereshkovich, K., 1930? (Box 32, Folder 21)
        - Vasil'ev, N., 1930 (Box 32, Folder 22)
        - Verhovskoy, R., April 1929 (Box 32, Folder 23)
        - Vinogradov, S., 1930 (Box 32, Folder 24)
        - Zaretskii, N., June 1933 (Box 32, Folder 25)
      - General, "Russkaia zhivopis' i prikladnoe iskustvo v Konstantinopole", typescript, undated (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - File 28, 1924-1934 (Boxes 32-33)
    - Russian art, printed matter
      - Brochures and periodicals
        - Art Russe Ancien et Moderne, Palais des Beaux-Arts de Bruxelles, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 27)
        - Exposition d'Art Russe, Paris, 1932 (Box 32, Folder 28)
        - L'Art Russe à Paris, Paris, 1931 (Box 32, Folder 29)
        - Perzvony, No., 14, 1926 (Box 33, Folder 1)
        - Velika Izlozhba Ruske Umetnosti, Belgrade, 1930 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Clippings, 1929-1934 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - File 29, 1915-1936 (Box 33)
    Russian drama and theater, actors and theatrical groups. Includes correspondence, printed matter, programs.
    - Russian drama and theater
      - Correspondence, including biographical material and printed matter
        - Barabanov, N., June 1929-September 1930 (Box 33, Folder 4)
        - Bertenson, S., September 1936 (Box 33, Folder 5)
        - Driesen, Baron N., April 1930 (Box 33, Folder 6)
        - Evreinov, N., February 1930 (Box 33, Folder 7)
        - Grech, V., includes typescript report re Moskovskii KHudozhestvennyi Teatr abroad, undated (Box 33, Folder 8)
        - Kasatkin-Rostovskii, Prince F. re D. Kirov and "Intimnyi Teatr", miscellaneous material, undated (Box 33, Folder 9)
        - Massalitinov, N., July 1930 (Box 33, Folder 10)
        - Rakitin, IU. (Ionin, IU.), March 1931 (Box 33, Folder 11)
        - Ranevskii, B., includes programs and photographs, 1915-October 1937 (Box 33, Folder 12)
        - Ryndina, L., typescript report and miscellaneous material re Russian theater in Berlin, 1930 (Box 33, Folder 13)
        - Sanin, A., July, 1930 (Box 33, Folder 14)
        - Vedrinskaia, M., undated (Box 33, Folder 15)
        - ZHurov-Andoga, V., June-August 1929 (Box 33, Folder 16)
      - Printed matter
        - Brochures and periodicals
          - Artisty Moskovskago KHudozhesvennago Teatra za Rubezhom, Prague, 1922 (Box 33, Folder 17)
          - "Russkii Dom Imeni Imperatora Nikolaia II", (Yugoslavia), programs, 1936 (Box 33, Folder 18)
            Available on microfilm reel 33
          - Russkii Teatr v Latvii, miscellaneous material, 1921-1931 (Box 33, Folder 19)
          - "Chauve-Souris, Théâtre de Nikita Balieff"
            - Correspondence and clippings (Box 33, Folder 20)
            - 1930-1931 (Box 33, Folder 21)
            - Illustrated programs, 1925-1927
      - Clippings
        - General, 1929-1934 (Box 33, Folder 22)
        - "Teatr Mikhaila CHekhova", 1930-1931 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - File 30, 1929-1934 (Box 34)
    Russian ballet, film and film actors. Includes correspondence, printed matter, programs.
    - Russian ballet
      - Correspondence, including biographical material and printed matter
        - Isachenko, K., November 1930 (Box 34, Folder 1)
        - Fokin, M., October 1931 (Box 34, Folder 2)
        - Grigor'ev, S., March 1930 (Box 34, Folder 3)
        - Karsavina, T., January-August 1930 (Box 34, Folder 4)
        - Kshesinskaia, M., clippings, 1930 (Box 34, Folder 5)
        - Leonidova, I., August 1930-May 1932 (Box 34, Folder 6)
        - Nemchinova, V., miscellaneous clippings and article in Le Théâtre et la vie, January 1930 (Box 34, Folder 7)
        - Nizhinskaia, B., October 1930 (Box 34, Folder 8)
        - Novikov, L. (includes M. Bakhrushin), September 1929 (Box 34, Folder 9)
        - Pavlova, A., typescript biography and clippings, April 1931 (Box 34, Folder 10)
        - Pourpiche, T., May 1931 (Box 34, Folder 11)
        - Riabushinskaia, T., August 1932 (Box 34, Folder 12)
        - Rostov, D., March 1930 (Box 34, Folder 13)
        - Tumanova, T., clipping and program, 1930 (Box 34, Folder 14)
        - Vasil'ev, F., March 1931 (Box 34, Folder 15)
        - Volinin, A., article in Le Théâtre et la vie, November 1929 (Box 34, Folder 16)
      - Clippings
        - General
          - 1929-1930 (Box 34, Folder 17)
          - 1931-1934 (Box 34, Folder 18)
        - Diagilev, S., 1929-1930 (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Russian film and film actors
      - Correspondence, including biographical material and printed matter
        - Lebedev, I., August-September 1930 (Box 34, Folder 20)
        - Miklashevskii, K. (Constant Mic), March 1930 (Box 34, Folder 21)
        - Mosiukin, I., "Der Weisse Teufel" and other printed matter, undated (Box 34, Folder 22)
        - Visarov, M., October 1930 (Box 34, Folder 23)
      - Clippings, 1929-1930 (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - File 31, 1929-1934 (Box 35)
    Russian sports organizations and Russian Scouts. Miscellaneous material.
    - Russian sport
      - The Anglo-Russian Sports Club, miscellaneous material, also see correspondence with M. Bakhrushin, 1929-1931 (Box 35, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 34
      - Rossiiskaia Laun-Tennisnaia Federatsiia, Ezhegodnik (Annuaire de la Fédération Russe de Lawn Tennis), printed copy, 1, 1930-93 (Box 35, Folder 2-3)
    - Russian Scouts (Razvedchiki)
      - National oranizations
        - Bulgaria
          - Karpinskii, N., handwritten report re scouting in Bulgaria, October 1930 (Box 35, Folder 4)
          - "Kompas", typescript monthly magazine, 1923-1924 (Box 35, Folder 5)
        - Belgium, Pomni Rossiiu, printed copy, June 1930 (Box 35, Folder 6)
        - China, SHtab Brigady Razvedchikov v Manzhurii, miscellaneous publications, undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
        - France
          - Miscellaneous orders, reports and official correspondence, typescript, 1929-1932 (Box 35, Folder 8)
          - Printed matter, including clippings, 1929-1931 (Box 35, Folder 9)
        - United States, includes correspondence with Col. A. Pantiukhov; Russian Boy Scouts, printed copy, and Russian Girl Guide leaflet, 1929 (Box 35, Folder 10)
        - Yugoslavia, SHtab-Kvartira Russkikh Odinochnykh Skautov, miscellaneous typescript material, 1930-1931 (Box 35, Folder 11)
        - Clippings, 1930-1934 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Photographs (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - File 32, 1922-1932 (Boxes 35-36)
    "Russkii Sokol", miscellaneous material.
    - "Russkii Sokol"
      - Bulgaria, miscellaneous material, 1927-1930 (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - Czechoslovakia
        - Report, typescript, 1931 (Box 36, Folder 1)
        - Printed matter
          - Materialy VI-go S"ezda Kraevogo Soiuza Russkago Sokol'stva v Korolevstve S.KH.S., 1929 (Box 36, Folder 2)
          - Russkii Sokol'skii Vestnik, 1927-1932 (Box 36, Folder 3)
          - Sokol'stvo, ego ideia, razvitie i organizatsiia, 1922 (Box 36, Folder 4)
            Available on microfilm reel 35
          - Clippings and appeals, 1929-1932 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - France, miscellaneous correspondence and clippings, 1929-1931 (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - Latvia, handwritten report, 1932 (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Yugoslavia
        - Miscellaneous material, 1926-1929 (Box 36, Folder 8)
        - Russkii Sokol, printed copies, 1928-1930 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - File 33, 1926-1933 (Boxes 36-37)
    Miscellaneous organizations and community groups. Correspondence, reports and printed matter.
    - List of unions and organizations, typescript, undated (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous organizations and community groups
      - Brat'ia Russkoi Pravdy, "Boevaia Pes'nia" and Biulleten', typescript, 1932 (Box 36, Folder 11)
      - "Den' Kul'tury", Prague and Harbin, miscellaneous material, 1930 (Box 36, Folder 12)
      - CHeshko-Russkoe Obshchestvo v Prage dlia vzaimnago Kredita, miscellaneous typescript material, 1932 (Box 36, Folder 13)
      - Edinnaia Aktivnaia Organizatsiia Spaseniia Rossii, typescript, 1932 (Box 36, Folder 14)
      - Imperatorskii S.-Peterburgskii Universitet, reunion programs, 1926-1929 (Box 36, Folder 15)
      - KHarbinski Komitet Pomoshchi Russkim Bezhentsam, miscellaneous printed matter, 1931-1932 (Box 36, Folder 16)
      - Komitet protesta protiv razrushenia KHrama KHrista Spasitelia, printed brochure, undated (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - Mezhdunarodnoe Soglashenie po Bor'be s III Internatsionalom, Russian section in Bulgaria, protocol, September 1929 (Box 36, Folder 18)
      - Natsional'nyi Soiuz Russkoi Molodezhy, typescript reports, 1929 (Box 36, Folder 19)
      - Natsional'nyia Grupirovki v Parizhe, report on meetings at conference, typescript, September 1932 (Box 36, Folder 20)
      - Obshchestvo Severian v Velikobritanii, printed copy, 1928 (Box 36, Folder 21)
      - Obshchestvo Vzaimopomoshchi Russkikh ZHenshchin, Prague, miscellaneous typescript material, 1930 (Box 36, Folder 22)
      - Petrogradskii Mezhdunarodnyi Bank, clippings, 1930 (Box 36, Folder 23)
      - Russkie Fashisty, Fashist, printed copy, July-August, 1933 (Box 36, Folder 24)
      - Russkoe Obshchestvo Filatelistov, miscellaneous material, 1930 (Box 36, Folder 25)